Eunice K. Shriver:
Tonight, in this great stadium,
a new legend is born.
You, athletes,
are the heroes of that legend.
You have taught us
that what truly counts
is the courageous spirit
and the generous heart.
The right to play
on any playing field?
You have earned it.
The right to study
in any school?
You have earned it.
The right to hold a job?
The right to be
anyone's neighbor?
You have earned it.
[ Cheers and applause ]
The days of separation
and segregation are over.
As the philosopher wrote,
"After conquering the winds and
the waves, tides and gravity,
we shall harness
energies of love,
and then, for the second time
in the history of the world,
man will discover fire."
♪♪